Vitaly Podkopaev

Date of Birth: 21-June-1985

Nationality: Germany Marital Status: Married

Email: vitaly.podkopaev@outlook.com

Mobile: +49 160 90264523

Address: Hoeninger Weg 116, 50969 Cologne, Germany



Management Consultant & Commercial Strategy Expert

5 years experience in management consulting and commercial strategy with 30+ projects in Central and East Europe, Middle East, North Africa and Asia Pacific regions. Certified project management expertise with strong problem solving, analytical and leadership skills through strategic consulting projects and MBA program at IE Business School. Profound understanding of the Telecommunication/Technology ecosystem, specialized in corporate and commercial strategies, carrier/product launches, customer experience, strategic partnerships with technical focus on Mobile Broadband, Mobile Financial Services, Fixed-Mobile Convergence and B2B ICT services (Cloud, M2M). Comfortable working in a dynamic environment at all levels with excellent interpersonal and cross-cultural competences through living abroad and business development in CIS and SEA regions.

Professional Experience

Deutsche Telekom, Bonn, Germany **Senior Expert Commercial Strategy & Steering Europe**

January 2016 – to date

- Project Management role in a strategy implementation review project for the Integrated Network Strategy (INS) success within the European operations on HQ and subsidiary level
- Commercial and strategic allocation of resources for specific European subsidiaries
- Priorization of commercial transformational topics for the Group wide annual budgeting process
- Refinement and implementation of value KPIs to improve return on market invest and value add
- Assessment of subsidiary performance and market positioning compared to competition
- Implementation of Value Based Steering (VBS) for improved data monetization and CLV
- Identification of KPIs to improve omni-channel customer experience (CX) across main touch points

Detecon Int. (Deutsche Telekom Group), Cologne, Germany Management Consultant Strategy, Innovation, Marketing, Sales

November 2011 – December 2015

- 30+ projects in strategic, commercial and technical domains in CEE, MENA and APAC regions
- Project Management and Commercial Stream Lead of an LTE strategy development and rollout plan.
 Development of a WiMAX to LTE migration strategy and product roadmap in MENA
- Delivered corporate and commercial strategies for incumbent operators in Russia / Kazakhstan
- Project Management of a B2B2C M2M proposition "In-Car-WiFi" for an automotive client
- Developed a corporate strategy and CDMA migration strategy for an incumbent fixed line operator
- Designed a marketing strategy and user interaction process model for a start-up in a corporate incubator
- Managed the development of a B2B2C digital authentication / secure identification proposition solution
- Development of a CAPEX efficiency tool with identification of 30% CAPEX reduction potential
- Co-created the commercial business plan and go-to-market strategy for an LTE greenfield operator
- From scratch development of an Operator-to-Operator Partner Program for a Telco client
- Conducted topic and business development in Mobile Financial Services in Russia and UAE

Detecon Asia-Pacific, Bangkok, Thailand **Office Secondment**

March 2014 - June 2014

- Prepared a tender offer for a post-merger integration plan for two major integrated Telcos in SEA
- Designed an LTE rollout strategy at one of the key operators in Malaysia
- Set up a tender pitch for a divestment of shares strategy for the incumbent operator in Nepal
- Performed a 3G proposition review and developed 4G value proposition for a top 3 operator in Thailand
- Managed an proposal preparation on "Wholesale Strategy" for one of the key operators in Indonesia

Detecon CIS, Moscow, Russia

June 2011 – September 2011

- Summer Trainee
 - Developed tender proposals in commercial and technical domains for clients in Russia and Kazakhstan
 - Project Management of a competitive analysis of the Telco consulting market in CIS countries
 - Developed a market entry strategy for a IPTV and WiMAX proposition for a fixed line operator in Russia

KPMG Advisory, Dusseldorf, Germany **Trainee**, **Performance & Technology**

January 2011 - March 2011

Full Professional Proficiency

Education

IE Business School, Madrid, Spain Master of Business Administration (MBA)	September 2015 – December 2016
Ruhr-University of Bochum, Bochum, Germany Business Administration & Social Science	2005 – 2010
Université de Perpignan Via Domitia, Perpignan, France Exchange Semester	2008 – 2009
German Embassy School, Moscow, Russia A-Levels / German Abitur	1992 – 2005

Language Skills / Certifications

•
Native or Bilingual Proficiency
Native or Bilingual Proficiency
Limited Professional Proficiency
Since April 2015
Since July 2016
Since May 2016
Advanced Level

Interests

Trends and strategies in the technology / telecom sector, Emerging Economies, OTTs, Digital Transformation, Internet Economy, Entrepreneurship, Literature, Sports (Running, Basketball, Squash, Muay Thai).

Togravael

English